Guide to the AIDSWORK of Tompkins County records, 1987-1994
AIDSWORK of Tompkins County records, 1987-1994
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
AIDSWORK of Tompkins County records, 1987-1994
7324
AIDSWORK of Tompkins County (N.Y.)
14.4 cubic ft.
Manuscripts, broadsides, photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Meeting minutes, budgets, grant proposals, broadsides, and some correspondence from Tompkins County AIDS Task Force and AIDS Work; also subject files, office files, material from other AIDS organizations, photographs, and other material.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Tompkins County AIDS Task Force formed in late 1985 to mobilize a countywide response to the AIDS epidemic. In late 1988 the name changed to AIDSWORK: HIV Support and Information for Tompkins County.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Meeting minutes, budgets, grant proposals, broadsides, and some correspondence from Tompkins County AIDS Task Force and AIDS Work; also subject files, office files, material from other AIDS organizations, photographs, and other material. Posters that duplicated ones in collection #51-1-2746 were removed. A list of these posters is provided at the end of the guide.
SUBJECTS
Names:
AIDS Work: HIV Support and Information for Tompkins County.; Tompkins County AIDS Task Force.
Subjects:
AIDS (Disease)--New York--Tompkins County.; AIDS phobia--New York--Tompkins County.; Bisexuality.; Gay men.; Homosexuality, Male.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Original Accession (list available)
Box 1
Series II. Educational Office Files
Boxes 2-7
Series III. Other AIDS Organizations
Boxes 8-10
Series IV. Subject Files
Boxes 11-14
Series V. Resource Material
Boxes 15-16
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Original accession (list available)
  - Bylaws, membership lists, financial papers, grant proposals, and AIDS Hostel papers. (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
  - AIDSWORK Minutes, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - AIDSWORK Minutes, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - AIDSWORK Minutes, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - AIDSWORK Publications (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Working Projects (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Safe Sex Slogans (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Broadsides (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - AIDS Background and Technical Material (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Series II. Education Office Files (Box 2-7)
- Series III. Other AIDS Organizations (Box 8-10)
- Series IV. Subject Files (Box 11-14)
- Series V. Resource Material
  - English and Spanish language AIDS pamphlets, ca. 1985-1996 (Box 15)
  - Cornell Biology and Society 451, "AIDS and Society" materials, 1989-90 (Box 15)
  - AIDS Work's Community Training Workshop resource manual, 1993-94 (Box 15)
  - City, regional, and state resources for social and medical support (Box 15)
  - "AIDS: An Epidemic of Fear, Discrimination in the Health Services of Tompkins County," a group research project, October 11, 1990 (Box 16)
  - City, regional, and state resources for social and medical support, ca. 1988-90 (Box 16)
  - Poster: "Al cumplir los 17, me enteré que tenía el HIV..." (Box 17)
  - Poster: "A United Community Will Conquer AIDS." (one in English, one in Spanish) (Box 17)
  - Poster: Ithaca Breast Cancer Alliance Walkathon advertisement, Oct. 22, 1994 (Box 17)
  - Poster: "'Let me help you.' If you want him to use a condom..." (Box 17)
  - Poster: "Sharing the Challenge: World AIDS Day", Dec. 1, 1991 (Box 17)
  - Poster: "The Faces Of The Presbyterian Church Could Also Be The Faces Of AIDS" (Box 17)
  - Poster: "Universal precautions to prevent infection with HIV when assisting at childbirth" (Box 17)
  - Poster: "World AIDS Day: Time To Act!" Dec. 1 1993 (Box 17)
  - Poster: "WVBR 93.5 FM Rocks Ithaca", advertising ticket sales (?) benefiting AIDSWork (Box 17)
SEPARATED MATERIAL
All of these posters can be found in collection #51-1-2746. Removed posters are listed below by the heading or first couple words of the poster. Simply search the 51-1-2746 guide for the titles found here.
AIDS Affects All, Cornell multilingual poster
AIDS is a problem for Hispanics, too. (English and Spanish)
Ayudando una persona que tiene SIDA
¿Como se adquiere el SIDA?
El futuro esta en tus manos.
El licor, el crack y otras drogas te ponen en riesgo de contraer el SIDA. (Spanish and English)
El dejo de inyectarse drogas
El SIDA no discrimina.
Getting High Doesn't Cause AIDS.
How much do your children know about AIDS?
How to Avoid AIDS: A Few Tips.
How Would You Deal With It If One Of You Got AIDS?
If You Are HIV Positive (GMHC poster, Spanish and English)
If You're Dabbling In Drugs
If Your Man Is Dabbling In Drugs
It might take more than motherwit to tell my children what to do about AIDS.
Most people think HIV is only a problem in big cities.
No Matter What Shape You're In, Anyone Can Get The AIDS Virus.
On the wrong track.
Papi, ponte el sombrero.
¿Quien cuidara de tus seres querido si tu faltas?
Sharing Needles Can Get You More Than High.
She shows all the signs of having HIV.
Since I got HIV, all I want to do is tell women that love alone won't protect them.
There's a simple way to prevent AIDS.
Today, almost one million Americans are infected with HIV.
When I found out I had HIV at age 17, I learned that anyone can get it.
Why there's a connection between sexually transmitted disease and AIDS. (English and Spanish)
You Won't Get AIDS From A Bug Bite
You Won't Get AIDS From A Public Pool.
You Won't Get AIDS From Hide 'N' Seek
You Won't Get AIDS In A Restaurant